# **Huiwen (Tracy) Jiang**

Los Angeles, California

(213)-245-4140 | huiwenji@usc.edu | www.linkedin.com/in/huiwen-jiang/

## **SUMMARY**

Master of science with strong programming, analytical and mathematical skills. 3+ years of hands on programming experience in wide range of projects, including full-stack web application development, Android app development and machine learning. Seeking full-time software engineer position

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **University of Southern California**

Los Angeles, CA

MS in Industrial & Systems Engineering (Analytics track); GPA:3.9/4.0

Aug 2018 - May 2020 (Expected)

• Course: Analysis of Algorithms, Machine Learning for Data Science, Foundations and Applications of Data Mining, Performance Analysis using Markov Models, Optimization methods for analytics, Fraud analytics

# **Beijing University of Aeronautics & Astronautic**

Beijing, China

• BS in Computational Material Science; GPA:3.5/4.0; Dean's List.

Aug 2014 - May 2018

#### SKILLS

Languages: Java, Python (pySpark, Tensorflow), HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Scala

Technologies: React.js, Express.js, AWS, Google Cloud, Github, JQuery, MapReduce, Bootstrap, Docker, Kubernete

Database: Relational databases (MySQL, Postgres) and NoSQL databases (MongoDB)

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Specifio, Inc.

Los Angeles, CA

Software Engineer Intern

Sep 2019 - Dec 2019

- Responsible for the improvement of fully-automated patent drafting service
- Implemented pptx file generation based on customers' claims using Java Aspose and tested with JUnit 5
- Handled end-to-end development, including coding, testing, debugging and troubleshooting
- Dockerized and deployed Java project via CI/CD pipeline using Docker and Jenkins

#### Homelink Real Estate Agency Co., Ltd

Beijing, China

Data Engineer intern

June 2018 - Aug 2018

- Worked in a team of ten responsible for improving website and its conversion rate to increase houses sales
- Constructed a multi-step workflow in Python and Spark(Scala) to pre-process clickstream data and implemented
  Web UI based on React.js and bootstrap
- Built real-time, low-latency machine learning models and recommendation systems with Python; tested and optimized the performance of online house recommendation which increased conversion rate by 15.38%

# **PROJECTS**

#### Perfect recipe - Node.JS Web Service (Full-Stack Development)

June 2019 - Aug 2019

- Developed a dynamic web page for users to share recipes, write comments and get personalized recommendation Back End:
- Utilized Express Framework in node.JS with RESTful APIs to handle HTTP requests and responses
- Built NoSQL databases (MongoDB) to manage data of recipes and users' preference
- Designed algorithms (e.g., content-based recommendation) to implement recipe recommendation with Python
- Deployed server side to Amazon EC2 which is able to handle 150 queries per second tested by Apache JMeter *Front End:*
- Designed an interactive web page utilizing BootStrap

## **VizAssist - An Android App Using Cloud OCR**

Aug 2019 - Sep 2019

- Developed a mobile app to assist blind users with text reading tasks by translating photos to text message
- Developed an Android Camera App utilizing Talkback, Scanner tools as client side based on Gradle, Android SDK
- Utilized Espresso to write Android Integration Testing and utilized Robolectic to write Android Unit Testing
- Wrote Java servlet to handle HTTP requests and responses and connect to Google Vision API
- Deployed on GCE VM with docker for End-to-end interaction flow and scaled on Google Kubernetes Engine

# **Credit Card Transaction Fraud Detection Project.**

Jan 2019 - Feb 2019

- Designed and developed a project aimed at detecting credit card transaction fraud using supervised algorithms
- Implemented feature extraction based on sliding time window and filtered features using Kolmogorov-Smirnov
- Performed Logistic Regression, Random Forest, XGBoost, SVM and Neural Network models with Python
- Evaluated and selected algorithm with best performance and achieved fraud detection rate of 96.75%